<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>/</id><title>hacker0ni</title><subtitle>A minimal blog that I keep to share my ideas, findings, guides and thoughts mainly on cyber security.</subtitle> <updated>2023-10-20T20:58:14+00:00</updated> <author> <name>Mustafa B. Polat</name> <uri>/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2023 Mustafa B. Polat </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>The HTTP/2 Rapid Reset Vulnerability: A Critical Flaw in Modern Web Communication</title><link href="/posts/http-2-reset-vuln/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The HTTP/2 Rapid Reset Vulnerability: A Critical Flaw in Modern Web Communication" /><published>2023-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2023-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/http-2-reset-vuln/</id> <content src="/posts/http-2-reset-vuln/" /> <author> <name>hacker0ni</name> </author> <category term="General" /> <summary> The HTTP/2 Rapid Reset Vulnerability: A Critical Flaw in Modern Web Communication Introduction In the realm of web communication protocols, HTTP/2 has been a game-changer. It was designed to improve the efficiency of data transfer between clients and servers, offering enhanced speed and performance over its predecessor, HTTP/1.1. However, like all technological advancements, it’s not immune t... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Dropping Ransomware Payouts and Why This Is Good For The Industry</title><link href="/posts/ransomware-payout-drop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dropping Ransomware Payouts and Why This Is Good For The Industry" /><published>2023-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2023-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/ransomware-payout-drop/</id> <content src="/posts/ransomware-payout-drop/" /> <author> <name>hacker0ni</name> </author> <category term="General" /> <summary> Intro Ransomware attacks have been a major concern for individuals and organizations alike in recent years. These attacks involve hackers encrypting a victim’s data and demanding payment in exchange for the decryption key. According to a recent report, ransomware payouts have dropped by 40%. While this may seem like bad news for victims of ransomware attacks, it is actually a positive develop... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Building Your Own Open-Source SIEM, Part I: AAAAAH!</title><link href="/posts/siem-part-I/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building Your Own Open-Source SIEM, Part I: AAAAAH!" /><published>2022-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2022-04-19T04:19:57+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/siem-part-I/</id> <content src="/posts/siem-part-I/" /> <author> <name>hacker0ni</name> </author> <category term="Guides" /> <summary> Intro This will be a post series where I discuss the details of an open-source SIEM and how you can deploy it on your own infrastructure. This will heavily focus on Security Onion 2 as it gives us nice out-of-the-box functionality. The aim of this series is not to promote any product(s), but to show you that with a little work and some patience, a lot can be achieved. To SIEM or not to SIEM T... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Implementing File Integrity Monitoring with Osquery</title><link href="/posts/fim-osquery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Implementing File Integrity Monitoring with Osquery" /><published>2022-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2022-02-22T02:50:03+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/fim-osquery/</id> <content src="/posts/fim-osquery/" /> <author> <name>hacker0ni</name> </author> <category term="Guides" /> <summary> In this post I’d like to talk a bit about file integrity monitoring and how you can implement it using Osquery. Let’s jump in. Requirements: Osquery installation Basic understanding of the Linux filesystem Integrity One of the main legs of the CIA triad is integrity. Maintaining the integrity of system files is important because these files decide the outcome of the binaries that we ex... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Linux Memory Forensics</title><link href="/posts/linux-memory-forensics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linux Memory Forensics" /><published>2022-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2022-02-16T03:53:14+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/linux-memory-forensics/</id> <content src="/posts/linux-memory-forensics/" /> <author> <name>hacker0ni</name> </author> <category term="Forensics" /> <summary> We can sum up forensic analysis as the different methods used in evidence acquisition, analysis of evidence, and documentation of the consequences of a security incident. After a confirmed security breach, a forensic analysis usually takes place to understand better what went on in a compromised system. There are numerous sources of evidence that you can analyze to make defensible claims about ... </summary> </entry> </feed>
